<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>btc-provider on networked subject</title>
    <link>https://subject.network/tags/btc-provider/</link>
    <description>Recent content in btc-provider on networked subject</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 21:15:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://subject.network/tags/btc-provider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring your Urbit Bitcoin wallet</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/btc-wallet-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 21:15:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/btc-wallet-config/</guid>
      <description>Late 2021 Note: This guide is now largely outmoded; %btc-wallet now comes installed out of the box and does not need to be manually installed; the dojo commands have been updated.    The day has finally arrived: May 27 saw a major update to Urbit, and the public release of a bitcoin wallet and the ability to send and receive payments. Your ship provides an identity layer on top of bitcoin &amp;ndash; you can tell your planet to send money to ~sampel-palnet, and Urbit takes care of the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Urbit-BTC integration with a Pi full node</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/pi-fullnode-urbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 17:55:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/pi-fullnode-urbit/</guid>
      <description>Note: Urbit&amp;rsquo;s Bitcoin wallet was launched in May 2021. You can learn how to use it here
Introduction As you may have heard, Urbit is due to receive support for Bitcoin in th near future. Thanks to the efforts of ~timluc-miptev in fulfilling a bounty for an Urbit-native bitcoin wallet and RPC support &amp;ndash; a suite called btc-agents &amp;ndash; you will be able to send and receive bitcoin with other pilots on the network, by connecting your ship to a provider, which itself is connected to a bitcoin full node running the Electrs rustlang Electrum Server implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin on Urbit With ~timluc-miptev</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/bitcoin-with-timluc-miptev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:28:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/bitcoin-with-timluc-miptev/</guid>
      <description>Note: Urbit&amp;rsquo;s Bitcoin wallet was launched in May 2021. You can learn how to use it here.
Recently it was announced that an Urbit grant bounty was completed, for software that would act as an Urbit-native bitcoin wallet and a bridge to mediate between a ship and an external BTC full node. ~timluc-miptev, the developer who fulfilled the grant, was generous enough to spend some time with me for an interview, conducted over the course of a couple of days in a chat channel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>