<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>urbit on networked subject</title>
    <link>https://subject.network/tags/urbit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in urbit on networked subject</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 14:00:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://subject.network/tags/urbit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates &amp; announcements: Late 2021</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/updates-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 14:00:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/updates-announcements/</guid>
      <description>This blog has been quiet for a few months, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t confuse that with a lack of activity.
I was awarded the opportunity to fulfill a grant for the Urbit Foundation, doing writing for urbit.org. You can see the first results here &amp;ndash; the Star operators&amp;rsquo; guide and Galaxy operators&amp;rsquo; guide, on the new Operators microsite. During the summer I was very graciously hosted on an episode of The Stack, a podcast about Urbit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: A Topiary</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/topiary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 20:58:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/topiary/</guid>
      <description>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a proper post, but rather a small announcement. I recently wrote an essay that was published on the urbit.org blog, which I will link here rather than repost. It is a modest attempt at contextualizing Urbit within the history of hypertext and hypermedia, and in particular their relation to %graph-store.
A big thank you to all those who provided feedback and edited it &amp;ndash; particularly Matt, L, James and Hadden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring your Urbit Bitcoin wallet</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/btc-wallet-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 21:15:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/btc-wallet-config/</guid>
      <description>Late 2021 Note: This guide is now largely outmoded; %btc-wallet now comes installed out of the box and does not need to be manually installed; the dojo commands have been updated.    The day has finally arrived: May 27 saw a major update to Urbit, and the public release of a bitcoin wallet and the ability to send and receive payments. Your ship provides an identity layer on top of bitcoin &amp;ndash; you can tell your planet to send money to ~sampel-palnet, and Urbit takes care of the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building native Windows Urbit binaries</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/urbit-windows-binaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 18:13:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/urbit-windows-binaries/</guid>
      <description>Late 2021 Note: This guide is now largely outmoded; Urbit now has official Windows binaries, and Port now has a native Windows installer    Last month, a PR was published by locpyl-tidnyd to the Urbit Github, containing instructions and a build environment for the compilation of static, Windows-native Urbit executables(!), for the eventual purpose of an official Windows binary distribution. I am frankly amazed that this is even possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ames indirect connection fixes</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/galaxy-routing-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 18:00:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/galaxy-routing-nat/</guid>
      <description>Urbit&amp;rsquo;s networking protocol, %ames, uses peer-to-peer connections to let your ship talk to others, with all traffic transported over encrypted UDP. However, in order to allow your ship to discover the IP addresses of ships you want to talk to, you have to query the network &amp;ndash; specifically, your ship asks your star, which asks the galaxies. The answer gets relayed to you, and then you send your packets where they&amp;rsquo;re meant to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Mars: Spring 2021</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/state-urbit-spring-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 18:31:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/state-urbit-spring-2021/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In lieu of a tutorial or interview, I thought it would be useful to write a short summary of some of the developments surrounding Urbit in the last year. 2020-21 has been an eventful period for many reasons, but the pace of development on the Urbit project has been steady, and always in the direction of beauty and utility.
When I polled a chat group about their favorite recent improvements and features, several people mentioned its improved reliability, especially chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Urbit on Windows with Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/urbit-windows-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 13:10:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/urbit-windows-docker/</guid>
      <description>Late 2021 Note: This guide is now largely outmoded; Urbit now has official Windows binaries, and Port now has a native Windows installer    Introduction We&amp;rsquo;ve previously covered a method for running Urbit on a Windows PC, but it could be a little onerous for a novice. Specifically, it still involved a decent amount of command line Linux administration. Fortunately, it turns out there is an easier way to do things; recently, ~botter-nidnul wrote up a guide to running Urbit inside a container with Docker Desktop, and with his blessing I am going to elaborate on it with step-by-step instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Urbit-BTC integration with a Pi full node</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/pi-fullnode-urbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 17:55:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/pi-fullnode-urbit/</guid>
      <description>Note: Urbit&amp;rsquo;s Bitcoin wallet was launched in May 2021. You can learn how to use it here
Introduction As you may have heard, Urbit is due to receive support for Bitcoin in th near future. Thanks to the efforts of ~timluc-miptev in fulfilling a bounty for an Urbit-native bitcoin wallet and RPC support &amp;ndash; a suite called btc-agents &amp;ndash; you will be able to send and receive bitcoin with other pilots on the network, by connecting your ship to a provider, which itself is connected to a bitcoin full node running the Electrs rustlang Electrum Server implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Urbit TLS with Caddy</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/caddyserver-urbit-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:22:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/caddyserver-urbit-tls/</guid>
      <description>One of the first tutorials written for this site was a rundown on setting up an https reverse proxy for your Urbit using Nginx and Letsencrypt. Nginx and LE are fantastic pieces of software, but steps involved may seem a little intimidating if you&amp;rsquo;ve never set up a web server before.
In the last couple of weeks, a few people around the network (thanks ~silsyn-wathep!) have suggested using Caddy (alt. Caddyserver), a very lightweight and fast HTTP server suite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation about Tacen with ~mister-todteg</title>
      <link>https://subject.network/posts/tacen-mister-todteg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 11:35:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://subject.network/posts/tacen-mister-todteg/</guid>
      <description>A sentiment you&amp;rsquo;ll frequently come across is that the community on Urbit is very high-quality, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to meet friendly and interesting people. ~mister-todteg is an example of both &amp;ndash; his company Tacen is developing a semi-decentralized noncustodial crypto exchange platform, and he was kind enough to spend a couple of days telling me about it over chat. In this interview we chat about him, the details of his company, his personal history with Urbit, and his vision for the possibility of future integration between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>